<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eml:eml packageId="edi.199.4" system="https://pasta.edirepository.org"
  xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1"
  xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1  http://nis.lternet.edu/schemas/EML/eml-2.1.1/eml.xsd">
  <access authSystem="https://pasta.edirepository.org/authentication"
    order="allowFirst" scope="document" system="https://pasta.edirepository.org">
    <allow>
      <principal>uid=EDI,o=EDI,dc=edirepository,dc=org</principal>
      <permission>all</permission>
    </allow>
    <allow>
      <principal>uid=carylab6,o=EDI,dc=edirepository,dc=org</principal>
      <permission>all</permission>
    </allow>
    <allow>
      <principal>uid=ccarey,o=EDI,dc=edirepository,dc=org</principal>
      <permission>all</permission>
    </allow>
    <allow>
      <principal>public</principal>
      <permission>read</permission>
    </allow>
  </access>
  <dataset>
    <alternateIdentifier system="https://doi.org">doi:10.6073/pasta/7140e852f519fe8acd1f86927c0af763</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>Water chemistry time series for Beaverdam Reservoir, Carvins Cove Reservoir, Falling Creek Reservoir, Gatewood Reservoir, and Spring Hollow Reservoir in southwestern Virginia, USA 2013-2017</title>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Cayelan</givenName>
        <givenName>C.</givenName>
        <surName>Carey</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Virginia Tech</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>Cayelan@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8835-4476</userId>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Mary</givenName>
        <givenName>E.</givenName>
        <surName>Lofton</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Virginia Tech</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>melofton@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3270-1330</userId>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Alexandra</givenName>
        <givenName>B.</givenName>
        <surName>Gerling</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Virginia Tech</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>alexg13@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Ryan</givenName>
        <givenName>P.</givenName>
        <surName>McClure</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Virginia Tech</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>ryan333@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6370-3852</userId>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Jonathan</givenName>
        <givenName>P.</givenName>
        <surName>Doubek</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Virginia Tech</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>jpdoubek@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-2651-4715</userId>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Barbara</givenName>
        <givenName>R.</givenName>
        <surName>Niederlehner</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Virginia Tech</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>bniederl@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Kaitlin</givenName>
        <givenName>J.</givenName>
        <surName>Farrell</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Virginia Tech</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>farrellk@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4709-7749</userId>
    </creator>
    <pubDate>2018-07-11</pubDate>
    <abstract>
      <para>
  Depth profiles of dissolved organic carbon and total and dissolved
  nitrogen and phosphorus were sampled from 2013 to 2017 in five
  drinking water reservoirs in southwestern Virginia, USA. These
  reservoirs are: Beaverdam Reservoir (Vinton, Virginia), Carvins Cove
  Reservoir (Roanoke, Virginia), Falling Creek Reservoir (Vinton,
  Virginia), Gatewood Reservoir (Pulaski, Virginia), and Spring Hollow
  Reservoir (Salem, Virginia). Beaverdam, Carvins Cove, Falling Creek,
  and Spring Hollow Reservoirs are owned and operated by the Western
  Virginia Water Authority as primary or secondary drinking water
  sources for Roanoke, Virginia, and Gatewood Reservoir is a drinking
  water source for the Town of Pulaski, Virginia. The dataset consists
  of depth profiles of water chemistry samples measured at the deepest
  site of each reservoir adjacent to the dam. Additional water chemistry
  samples were collected at a gauged weir on Falling Creek Reservoir's
  primary inflow tributary. The samples were collected approximately
  fortnightly from March-April, weekly from May-October, and monthly
  from November-February.
</para>
    </abstract>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword>Carey Lab</keyword>
      <keyword>Virginia Tech</keyword>
      <keyword>Western Virginia Water Authority</keyword>
      <keyword>Falling Creek Reservoir</keyword>
      <keyword>Stream Team</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>carey lab controlled vocabulary</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword>Reservoir</keyword>
      <keyword>Lake</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>cuahsi controlled vocabulary</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword>Lakes</keyword>
      <keyword>nitrate</keyword>
      <keyword>soluble reactive phosphorus</keyword>
      <keyword>dissolved organic carbon</keyword>
      <keyword>ammonium</keyword>
      <keyword>total nitrogen</keyword>
      <keyword>total phosphorus</keyword>
      <keywordThesaurus>lter controlled vocabulary</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <intellectualRights>
      <para>
  This information is released under the Creative Commons license -
  Attribution - CC BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).
  The consumer of these data ("Data User" herein) is required
  to cite it appropriately in any publication that results from its use.
  The Data User should realize that these data may be actively used by
  others for ongoing research and that coordination may be necessary to
  prevent duplicate publication. The Data User is urged to contact the
  authors of these data if any questions about methodology or results
  occur. Where appropriate, the Data User is encouraged to consider
  collaboration or co-authorship with the authors. The Data User should
  realize that misinterpretation of data may occur if used out of
  context of the original study. While substantial efforts are made to
  ensure the accuracy of data and associated documentation, complete
  accuracy of data sets cannot be guaranteed. All data are made
  available "as is." The Data User should be aware, however,
  that data are updated periodically and it is the responsibility of the
  Data User to check for new versions of the data. The data authors and
  the repository where these data were obtained shall not be liable for
  damages resulting from any use or misinterpretation of the data. Thank
  you.
</para>
    </intellectualRights>
    <coverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Southwestern Virginia, USA, North America</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-119.95</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>28.53</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>69.0</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>28.38</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Beaverdam Reservoir is located in Vinton, Virginia, USA</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-79.824834</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-79.813848</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>37.322865</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>37.311961</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Carvins Cove Reservoir is located in Roanoke, Virginia, USA</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-79.978642</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-79.944052</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>37.409127</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>37.365345</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Falling Creek Reservoir is located in Vinton, Virginia, USA</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-79.839249</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-79.836009</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>37.309589</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>37.30266</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Gatewood Reservoir is located in Pulaski, Virginia, USA</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-80.89188</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-80.858492</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>37.054358</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>37.03819</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Spring Hollow Reservoir is located in Salem, Virginia, USA</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-80.179076</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-80.170407</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>37.231092</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>37.217594</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <temporalCoverage>
        <rangeOfDates>
          <beginDate>
            <calendarDate>2013-04-04</calendarDate>
          </beginDate>
          <endDate>
            <calendarDate>2017-12-11</calendarDate>
          </endDate>
        </rangeOfDates>
      </temporalCoverage>
    </coverage>
    <maintenance>
      <description>ongoing</description>
    </maintenance>
    <contact>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Cayelan</givenName>
        <givenName>C.</givenName>
        <surName>Carey</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>Virginia Tech</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>Cayelan@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8835-4476</userId>
    </contact>
    <methods>
      <methodStep>
        <description>
          <para>
  SAMPLING TIMES Most sampling occurred between the hours of 9:00 and
  15:00, and are denoted in the DateTime as 12:00. Some sampling
  occurred outside of these hours, including some overnight sampling;
  these instances are noted by the actual sampling time within the
  DateTime column. For more information about nighttime sampling, see
  Doubek et. al. 2018.
</para>
          <para>
  SAMPLE COLLECTION AND EQUIPMENT
</para>
          <para>
  Total nitrogen (TN) and total phosphorus (TP)
</para>
          <para>
  Unfiltered water samples were collected at specified depths for each
  reservoir using a 4L Van Dorn water sampler (Wildco, Yulee, Florida,
  USA). Sample timestamps for samples collected between approximately 9
  a.m. and 3 p.m. were standardized to noon. Samples collected for
  projects that required sample collection at specific times of day were
  standardized to the top of the hour during which they were collected
  (i.e., a sample timestamp of 16:00 indicates a sample taken between 4
  and 5 p.m.). Samples were stored in acid-washed 125 mL polypropylene
  bottles and frozen within 12 hours. Samples were generally analyzed
  within one year of collection date.
</para>
          <para>
  Soluble reactive phosphorus (SRP), nitrate (NO3), ammonium (NH4) and
  dissolved organic carbon (DOC)
</para>
          <para>
  Water samples were collected at specified depths for each reservoir
  using a Van Dorn water sampler and were filtered with a 0.7 _m glass
  fiber filter (Thomas Scientific GF/F) before being stored in
  acid-washed 125 mL polypropylene bottles. Sample timestamps for
  samples collected between approximately 9 a.m. and 3 p.m. were
  standardized to noon. Samples collected for projects that required
  sample collection at specific times of day were standardized to the
  top of the hour during which they were collected (i.e., a sample
  timestamp of 16:00 indicates a sample taken between 4 and 5 p.m.).
  Samples were frozen within 12 hours. Samples were generally analyzed
  within six months of collection date.
</para>
          <para>
  CHEMICAL ANALYSES AND EQUIPMENT
</para>
          <para>
  TN and TP
</para>
          <para>
  Samples were digested with alkaline persulfate (Patton and Kryskalla
  2003) and then analyzed colorimetrically using flow injection analysis
  (APHA 2005). TN was analyzed using the cadmium reduction method (APHA
  1998) and TP was analyzed using the ascorbic acid method (Murphy and
  Riley 1962) on a Lachat Instruments XYZ Autosampler ASX 520 Series and
  QuikChem Series 8500 (Lachat ASX 520 Series, Lachat Instruments,
  Loveland, Colorado, USA).
</para>
          <para>
  SRP, NO3, NH4
</para>
          <para>
  Samples were analyzed colorimetrically using flow injection analysis
  (APHA 2005). SRP was analyzed using the ascorbic acid method (Murphy
  and Riley 1962), NO3 was analyzed using the cadmium reduction method
  (APHA 1998), and NH4 was analyzed using the Berthelot Reaction method
  (Solorzano 1969, APHA 2005) with a common modification as to the
  source of the hypochlorite ion as described in Zhang et al. 1997 on a
  Lachat Instruments XYZ Autosampler ASX 520 Series and QuikChem Series
  8500 (Lachat ASX 520 Series, Lachat Instruments, Loveland, Colorado,
  USA).
</para>
          <para>
  DOC
</para>
          <para>
  DOC was analyzed using the persulfate catalytic method (Brenton and
  Arnett 1993) on a TOCA 1010 from OI Analytical from 2013-2016 (OI
  Analytical 1010 Total Organic Carbon Analyzer with 1051 autosampler,
  College Station, TX USA) and on a Vario TOC Cube from Elementar from
  2016-2017 (vario TOC cube, Elementar Analysensysteme GmbH, Hanau,
  Germany).
</para>
          <para>
  ADDITIONAL NOTES From 2013 to 2017, multiple whole-ecosystem
  manipulations were conducted at Falling Creek Reservoir. These
  manipulations include intermittent operation of hypolimnetic
  oxygenation and pulsed epilimnetic mixing engineering systems. For a
  detailed description of the hypolimnetic oxygenation engineered
  system, see Gerling et al. (2014) and for a detailed description of
  the epilimnetic mixing engineered system, see Chen et al. (2017).
  These systems were operated over time following Table 1 in Gerling et
  al. (2016), Table 1 in Munger et al. (2016), and Table 2 in McClure et
  al. (2018).
</para>
          <para>
  Chen, S., C. Lei, C.C. Carey, P.A. Gantzer, and J.C. Little. 2017.
  Predicting hypolimnetic oxygenation and epilimnetic mixing in a
  shallow eutrophic reservoir using a coupled three-dimensional
  hydrodynamic model. Water Resources Research. 53: 470-484. DOI:
  10.1002/2016WR019279
</para>
          <para>
  Gerling, A.B., Browne, R.G., Gantzer, P.A., Mobley, M.H., Little,
  J.C., and C.C. Carey. 2014. First report of the successful operation
  of a side stream supersaturation hypolimnetic oxygenation system in a
  eutrophic, shallow reservoir. Water Research. 67: 129-143. doi:
  10.1016/j.watres.2014.09.002
</para>
          <para>
  Gerling, A.B., Z.W. Munger, J.P. Doubek, K.D. Hamre, P.A. Gantzer,
  J.C. Little, and C.C. Carey. 2016. Whole-catchment manipulations of
  internal and external loading reveal the sensitivity of a century-old
  reservoir to hypoxia. Ecosystems. 19:555-571. DOI:
  10.1007/s10021-015-9951-0
</para>
          <para>
  McClure, R.P., K.D. Hamre, B.R. Niederlehner, Z.W. Munger, S. Chen,
  M.E. Lofton, M.E. Schreiber, and C.C. Carey. 2018 Metalimnetic oxygen
  minima alter the vertical profiles of carbon dioxide and methane in a
  managed freshwater reservoir. Science of the Total Environment 636:
  610-620. DOI: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.04.255
</para>
          <para>
  Munger, Z.W., C.C. Carey, A.B. Gerling, K.D. Hamre, J.P. Doubek, S.D.
  Klepatzki, R.P. McClure, and M.E. Schreiber. 2016. Effectiveness of
  hypolimnetic oxygenation for preventing accumulation of Fe and Mn in a
  drinking water reservoir. Water Research. 106: 1-14. DOI:
  10.1016/j.watres.2016.09.038.
</para>
          <para>
  REFERENCES
</para>
          <para>
  APHA. 1998. Standard methods for the examination of water and
  wastewater. 20th edn. Washington, DC: American Public Health
  Association.
</para>
          <para>
  APHA. 2005. Standard methods for the examination of water and
  wastewater. 21st edn. Washington, DC: American Public Health
  Association, American Water Works Association, Water Environment
  Federation.
</para>
          <para>
  Brenton R, Arnett T. 1993. Method of analysis by the U.S. Geological
  Survey National Water Quality Laboratory - Determination of dissolved
  organic carbon by UV-promoted persulfate oxidation and infrared
  spectrometry. Denver, CO: U.S. Geological Survey.
</para>
          <para>
  Murphy J, Riley JP. 1962. A modified single solution method for the
  determination of phosphate in natural waters. Anal Chim Acta 27:31.6.
</para>
          <para>
  Patton CJ, Kryskalla JR. 2003. Methods of Analysis by the U.S.
  Geological Survey National Water Quality Laboratory-Evaluation of
  Alkaline Persulfate Digestion as an Alternative to Kjeldahl Digestion
  for Determination of Total and Dissolved Nitrogen and Phosphorus in
  Water. Denver, CO: U.S. Geological Survey.
</para>
          <para>
  Revesz KM, Doctor DH. 2014. Automated determination of the stable
  carbon isotopic composition (_13C) of total dissolved inorganic carbon
  (DIC) and total nonpurgeable dissolved organic carbon (DOC) in aqueous
  samples: RSIL lab codes 1851 and 1852: U.S. Geological Survey
  Techniques and Methods, book 10, chap. C20, 38 p., http://
  dx.doi.org/10.3133/tm10C20.
</para>
          <para>
  Solorzano, L. 1969. Determination of ammonia in natural water by the
  phenolhypochlorite method. Limnol Oceanogr 14:799-801.
</para>
          <para>
  USEPA. 2004. RSKSOP-175 STANDARD OPERATING PROCEDURE Sample
  Preparation and Calculations for Dissolved Gas Analysis in Water
  Samples Using a GC Headspace Equilibration Technique, Revision No.2
  http://www.epa.gov/region1/info/testmethods/pdfs/RSKsop175v2.pdf
  Retrieved 20APR2015.
</para>
          <para>
  Zhang, J.Z., Orter, P., Fisher, Ch. J. and Moore, L.D. 1997.
  Determination of ammonia in estuarine and coastal waters by gas
  segmented flow colorimetric analysis. Methods for determination of
  chemical substances in marine and estuarine environmental matrices.
  2nd ed. EPA/7664-41-7.
</para>
        </description>
      </methodStep>
    </methods>
    <project>
      <title>No project title to report</title>
      <personnel>
        <individualName>
          <givenName>Cayelan</givenName>
          <surName>Carey</surName>
        </individualName>
        <electronicMailAddress>Cayelan@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
        <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8835-4476</userId>
        <role>Principal Investigator</role>
      </personnel>
      <funding>Western Virginia Water Authority</funding>
      <relatedProject>
        <title>Dynamics of coupled P-Fe-Mn cycling in drinking water reservoirs and implications for water quality</title>
        <personnel>
          <individualName>
            <givenName>Cayelan</givenName>
            <surName>Carey</surName>
          </individualName>
          <electronicMailAddress>Cayelan@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
          <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8835-4476</userId>
          <role>Principal Investigator</role>
        </personnel>
        <funding>Institute of Critical Technology and Applied Science</funding>
      </relatedProject>
      <relatedProject>
        <title>No project title to report</title>
        <personnel>
          <individualName>
            <givenName>Cayelan</givenName>
            <surName>Carey</surName>
          </individualName>
          <electronicMailAddress>Cayelan@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
          <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8835-4476</userId>
          <role>Principal Investigator</role>
        </personnel>
        <funding>Virginia Tech Global Change Center</funding>
      </relatedProject>
      <relatedProject>
        <title>No project title to report</title>
        <personnel>
          <individualName>
            <givenName>Cayelan</givenName>
            <surName>Carey</surName>
          </individualName>
          <electronicMailAddress>Cayelan@vt.edu</electronicMailAddress>
          <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8835-4476</userId>
          <role>Principal Investigator</role>
        </personnel>
        <funding>Fralin Life Sciences Institute</funding>
      </relatedProject>
    </project>
    <dataTable>
      <entityName>chemistry.csv</entityName>
      <entityDescription>Reservoir water chemistry dataset.</entityDescription>
      <physical>
        <objectName>chemistry.csv</objectName>
        <size unit="byte">155189</size>
        <authentication method="MD5">92151def9ff6f2d7b1491816b926619b</authentication>
        <dataFormat>
          <textFormat>
            <numHeaderLines>1</numHeaderLines>
            <recordDelimiter>\r\n</recordDelimiter>
            <attributeOrientation>column</attributeOrientation>
            <simpleDelimited>
              <fieldDelimiter>,</fieldDelimiter>
            </simpleDelimited>
          </textFormat>
        </dataFormat>
        <distribution>
          <online>
            <url>https://pasta.lternet.edu/package/data/eml/edi/199/4/da174082a3d924e989d3151924f9ef98</url>
          </online>
        </distribution>
      </physical>
      <attributeList>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Reservoir</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Three-letter code corresponding to sampled reservoir</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>string</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <nominal>
              <nonNumericDomain>
                <enumeratedDomain>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>BVR</code>
                    <definition>Beaverdam Reservoir</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>CCR</code>
                    <definition>Carvins Cove Reservoir</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>FCR</code>
                    <definition>Falling Creek Reservoir</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>GWR</code>
                    <definition>Gatewood Reservoir</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                  <codeDefinition>
                    <code>SHR</code>
                    <definition>Spring Hollow Reservoir</definition>
                  </codeDefinition>
                </enumeratedDomain>
              </nonNumericDomain>
            </nominal>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Site</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Sampling site within each reservoir; 50=Deep hole or site nearest to dam in each reservoir, 100=Inflow stream of Falling Creek Reservoir, 20=Upstream pelagic site nearest to inflow stream at Falling Creek Reservoir</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>dimensionless</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>natural</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">20</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">100</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>DateTime</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Date and time of sampling. All data were collected in the eastern time zone of the U.S.A., with daylight savings time observed</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>date</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <dateTime>
              <formatString>YYYY-MM-DD hh:mm:ss</formatString>
            </dateTime>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Depth_m</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Water depth where the sample was collected or sensor reading was measured</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>meter</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0.1</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">31</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>TN_ugL</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Total nitrogen concentration</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>microgramsPerLiter</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">36.6</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">3680</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>TP_ugL</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Total phosphorus concentration</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>microgramsPerLiter</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">247</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>NH4_ugL</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Ammonium concentration</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>microgramsPerLiter</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">1780</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>NO3NO2_ugL</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Nitrate-nitrite concentration</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>microgramsPerLiter</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">380</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>SRP_ugL</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Soluble reactive phosphorus concentration</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>microgramsPerLiter</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">119</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>DOC_mgL</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Dissolved organic carbon concentration</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>milligramsPerLiter</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>real</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0.2</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">18.3</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Flag_TN</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Data flag for total nitrogen (TN); 1 = sample not taken, 2 = instrument malfunction, 3 = sample below detection, 4 = negative value set to zero, 5 = demonic intrusion, 6 = non-standard method, 7 = sample run multiple times and values averaged</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>dimensionless</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>whole</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">67</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Flag_TP</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Data flag for total phosphorus (TP); 1 = sample not taken, 2 = instrument malfunction, 3 = sample below detection, 4 = negative value set to zero, 5 = demonic intrusion, 6 = non-standard method, 7 = sample run multiple times and values averaged</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>dimensionless</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>whole</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">67</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Flag_NH4</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Data flag for ammonium (NH4); 1 = sample not taken, 2 = instrument malfunction, 3 = sample below detection, 4 = negative value set to zero, 5 = demonic intrusion, 6 = non-standard method, 7 = sample run multiple times and values averaged</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>dimensionless</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>whole</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">7</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Flag_NO3NO2</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Data flag for nitrate nitrite (NO3NO2); 1 = sample not taken, 2 = instrument malfunction, 3 = sample below detection, 4 = negative value set to zero, 5 = demonic intrusion, 6 = non-standard method, 7 = sample run multiple times and values averaged</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>dimensionless</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>whole</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">7</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Flag_SRP</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Data flag for soluble reactive phosphorus (SRP); 1 = sample not taken, 2 = instrument malfunction, 3 = sample below detection, 4 = negative value set to zero, 5 = demonic intrusion, 6 = non-standard method, 7 = sample run multiple times and values averaged</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>dimensionless</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>whole</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">7</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
        <attribute>
          <attributeName>Flag_DOC</attributeName>
          <attributeDefinition>Data flag for dissolved organic carbon (DOC); 1 = sample not taken, 2 = instrument malfunction, 3 = sample below detection, 4 = negative value set to zero, 5 = demonic intrusion, 6 = non-standard method, 7 = sample run multiple times and values averaged</attributeDefinition>
          <storageType>float</storageType>
          <measurementScale>
            <ratio>
              <unit>
                <standardUnit>dimensionless</standardUnit>
              </unit>
              <numericDomain>
                <numberType>whole</numberType>
                <bounds>
                  <minimum exclusive="false">0</minimum>
                  <maximum exclusive="false">6</maximum>
                </bounds>
              </numericDomain>
            </ratio>
          </measurementScale>
          <missingValueCode>
            <code>NA</code>
            <codeExplanation>value is missing</codeExplanation>
          </missingValueCode>
        </attribute>
      </attributeList>
      <numberOfRecords>2469</numberOfRecords>
    </dataTable>
  </dataset>
</eml:eml>
